Josh Urban Davis

1 Huntley Road, Hanover, NH 03755 | 713 204 5173 | joshurbandavis@gmail.com | https://www.joshurbandavis.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS

• Novel Sensors Design • Generative Design • Ubiquitous Computing • Human-Computer Interactions • Post-Touch-Screen Interactive Devices • Machine Learning • Biofeedback • Virtual Reality • Human-AI Interaction • Accessibility • Enabling Technologies

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Dartmouth College, Hanover, NH. 2018-Present

Ph.D in Computer Science

Department of Computer Science Human Computer Interaction Lab

Advisors: Prof. Xing-Dong Yang, Prof. Michael Casey

Dartmouth College, Hanover, NH. 2016-2018

M.S. in Computer Science and Digital Arts

Bregman Media Labs and Department of Computer Science

Advisors: Prof. Michael Casey, Prof. Xing-Dong Yang, Prof. Grace Leslie

University of Houston, Houston, TX. 2016

B.S. Computer Science

B.F.A. Studio Arts

Cum Laude

Areas of Concentration: Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning, New Media,

Interactive Installation

A note on publication venues: in my primary area of research, Human Computer Interaction, the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI) is considered one of the best forums for dissemination of research results and covers the broad spectrum of research in Human Computer Interaction. The ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST) is of similar quality, but is focused on a particular sub-area of the field, namely interactive techniques and devices. Papers in these conferences are refereed as full papers, and have an acceptance rate of around 15-25% each year.

MANUSCRIPTS IN PREPARATION

- 1. **Josh Urban Davis**, Te-Yen Wu, Bo-shu Zhang, Athena Papadopoulos, Emily Whitening, Xing-Dong Yang. "TangibleCircuits: A Tangible and Audio Feedback Tool for Teaching Hardware Computing to User's with Visual Impairments Using 3D Printing and Smartphones." [Submitted to CHI 2020]
- 2. **Josh Urban Davis,** Yizhe Zu, Xing-Dong Yang. "PantoTouch: Enabling Precision Gestural Input on Smart Watches Using a Pantograph" [Submitted to CHI 2020]

- 3. Jun Gong, Teddy Sayed, **Josh Urban Davis**, Songlin Xu, Yao Zou, Yuke Wang, Xin Lui, Da-Yuan Huang, Xing-Dong Yang. "SpringBoard: A Haptic Feedback System for Breadboards Using Virtual Springs."

 [Submitted to CHI 2020]
- 4. Jun Gong, Teddy Sayed, **Josh Urban Davis**, Songlin Xu, Yao Zou, Yuke Wang, Xin Lui, Da-Yuan Huang, Xing-Dong Yang. "SpringBoard: A Haptic Feedback System for Breadboards Using Virtual Springs."

 [Submitted to CHI 2020]

PEER-REVIEWED PROCEEDINGS

- 1. **Josh Urban Davis**, Jun Gong, Yunxin Sun, Parmit Chilana, Xing-Dong Yang. "CircuitStyle: A System for Peripherally Reinforcing Best Practices in Hardawre Computin". *Proceedings of User Interfaces Software Technology (UIST)* New Orleans, LA. 2019.
- 2. **Josh Urban Davis**. "IllumiWear: A Bendable Interactive Fiber-Optic eTextile for Audio and Visual Interactions." *Proceedings of New Interfaces in Musical Expression (NIME)*. Porto Alegre, Brazil. 2019
- 3. Jun Gong, Xin Yang, Teddy Sayed, **Josh Urban Davis**, Xing-Dong Yang. "Indutivo: Contact-Based Object-Driven Interactions with Inductive Sensing." *Proceedings of User Interface Software Technology (UIST)*, Berlin, Germany. 2018.
- 4. **Josh Urban Davis.** "Postcards from the Electric Void: Interactive Generation of Animations, Images, and Sound Using Adversarial Learning". Second Workshop on Machine Learning for Creativity and Design, Neuro Information Systems Processing (NeruIPS). Montreal, QC. 2018
- 5. **Josh Urban Davis.** "The Gender Generator: Towards a Brain-Computer Interface for Evocation of Gender Dysphoria Symptoms." *Proceedings of the 8th Annual Workshop on Creative Applications of Brain-Computer Interfacing, Human Factors in Computing (CHI)*. Montreal, QC. 2018
- 6. Fatih Akdag, **Josh Urban Davis**, Christoph Eick. "A Computational Framework for Finding Interestingness Hotspots in Large Spatio-Temporal Grids." *Proceedings of the 3rd ACM SIGSPATIAL International Workshop on Analytics for Big Geospatial Data, BigSpatial* 2014.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

KDiscovery Lab, Dartmouth College, Graduate Student Researcher March 2018 - Present
☐ Prototyped post-touch screen devices and novel sensing techniques
Developed and evaluated novel interaction methods resulting in publication (<i>Human Factors in Computing CHI</i> and <i>User Interface Software Technology UIST</i>)

□ Collaborated with Kelley Center for the blind to implement enabling technologies for visually disabled users.
Bregmann Media Labs, Media Arts and Sciences Researcher February 2017 – February 2018
☐ Analyzed fMRI data for signal reconstruction of auditory stimuli
$\ \square$ Developed novel brain-computer interaction methods for creating paintings and music
\square Led experiment team in collection of EEG and user experience data
□ Presented and demonstrated brain-computer interaction techniques at multiple venues (Human Factors in Computing CHI and New Interfaces for Musical Expression NIME)
DALI Lab, Developer II August 2016 – February 2017
☐ Led team of designers and developers to create virtual reality and biofeedback systems
☐ Collaborated with NASA and the Space Medicine Laboratory at Geisel Medical School to create virtual reality content for space flights
☐ Prototyped biofeedback systems for virtual reality to provide assistive health and wellbeing
□ Developed and edited 360 video and 3D modeled VR environments with Unity and Adobe Creative Suite
BIO

Josh Urban Davis is a research based artist and engineer whose practice spans sculpture, filmmaking, projection, and site-specific performance and installations. He holds a BFA in studio art and BS in computer science as well as an MS in computer sciences and digital arts. Recent projects draw inspiration from speculative fiction to explore the relationship between emerging technologies, social relationships, and identity. Explicitly engaged with the very technologies that he critiques, Davis's work viscerally confronts the viewer, inviting contemplation of the role new technologies play in mediating and reimaging our understanding of reality, corporality, and identity. His work has been exhibited at D!iverseWorks, the Blaffer Art Museum, Art League, Houston, Black Visual Arts Center, Alternatives, Chandler Gallery, and others. They currently live in Hanover, NH with their cat, Nocturne, where they are pursuing a PhD in computer sciences at Dartmouth.

EXHIBITIONS AND PERFORMANCES

An Archive of Feeling, Chandler Gallery, Randolph, VT. 2019 New Century/New Materials, Heritage Gallery at Alternatives, Whitinsville, MA. 2019 IllumiWear: Concert for Fabric and Light, NIME, Puerto Alegre, Brazil. 2019 Science and Sonnets: Creative Turing Test, Pint of Science, Houston, TX. 2019 Lion's Den, BETA Theatre and DinoLion Productions, (Creative Technologist Collaborator) Houston, TX. 2019

Stabat Mater: For Voice and Electronics, SHIFT Festival, (Electronics and Visuals Collaborator) Hanover, NH. 2018

Postcards from the Electric Void, Artificial Intelligence and Art, Montreal, QC. 2018

Synapstraction, Digital Arts Expo, Black Visual Arts Center, Hanover, NH. 2017 Mixtape, Hardy and Nance Studios, Houston, TX. 2017

RedHoust, BETA Theatre and DinoLion Productions, (Script Writing Collaborator) Houston, TX. 2016

Drawing the Perfect Line, Box 13 Artspace, Lonestar Explosion Performance Art Biennale. Houston, TX. (Curated by Julia Wallace and Jonatan Lopez). 2015. The Big Machine, El Rincoln Sociale. Houston, TX 2015

Submission, Silver Street Studios. Houston, TX. 2014

Cohesion, Gallery M Squared, Houston TX. 2012 A Taste of Red Ink, G Gallery, Houston TX. 2012

The Big Show, Lawndale Contemporary Arts Center, Houston, TX. Runner-up: Best in Show (Juror: Larissa Harris, Curator, Queens Museum of Art, New York, NY) 2011 State Fair, DiverseWorks Alternative Art Space, Houston, TX. 2011 (Juror: Diane Barber, Executive Director, DiverseWorks Alternative Art Space, Houston, TX)

Luck of the Draw, DiverseWorks Alternative Art Space, Houston TX. 2011 East Austin Studio Tour, Home for Misfit Ideas, Austin, TX. 2011 (Juror: Lizzie Pelz, Curator, Home for Misfit Ideas, Austin, TX)

Ekphrastic: Dionesia, University of Houston Honors College, Houston TX. 2011

PUBLICITY

"Janus Turned" poem, "Vitrine #6", and "A Plea for Dorian Gray" images, Glass Mountain Literary Magazine 20 Feb. 2012.

"The Buried Orchestra" cover image, The Aletheia Literary Magazine 21 Feb. 2012.

Interview with Aetheia Literary Magazine Online. 14 Feb. 2012

Klaasmeyer, Kelly. "A State Affair." Houston Press 12 Oct. 2011.

Britt, Douglas. "DiverseWorks' State Fair Offers Alternative to Art Fairs." The Houston Chronicle 7 Sept. 2011.

Hancock, Hank. "Fair Game." Art + Culture 11 Sept. 2011.

"Op 1 No 5" image, The Aletheia Literary Magazine 15 Sept. 2011.

REFERENCES

Prof. Michael Casey

Director, Graduate Program in Digital Musics, Professor of Computer Science
Dartmouth College
Hallgarten Hall, Room 103
HB 6242

michael.a.casey@dartmouth.edu 603 646-9609

Prof. Xing-Dong Yang

Department of Computer Science
Dartmouth College
HB 6211

xing-dong.yang@dartmouth.edu

Prof. Grace Leslie

Department of Music Technology Georgia Institute of Technology

grace.leslie@gatech.edu

Prof. Lorie Loeb

Faculty Director, DALI Lab Research Professor Director, Digital Arts Program Dartmouth College HB 6211

lorie.loeb@dartmouth.edu 603-646-8726